Jahanzeb Sohail

iOS Developer

- +92 328 8846664
- sohailjahanzeb047@gmail.com
- Rawalpindi, Pakistar
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jahanzeb-sohail-047



PROFILE

As an experienced iOS developer with 5 years of industry experience, my expertise lies in developing robust and efficient mobile applications using Swift and Objective-C. Additionally, I also possess midlevel proficiency in Flutter, making me versatile in my approach to mobile app development.

SKILLS

iOS Development

Swift, Objective-C, Xcode IDE, UlKit, Swift ui, Snapkit, Core Data, GCD Multithreading, Push Notifications, Combine.

Debugging and Testing

Xcode debugger , UI testing , Unit testing

Mobile App Architecture

MVC, MVVM, SOLID, CLEAN

Flutter

Dart , Android studio, Widgets , State management,

Integrations

Rest Apis, Firebase, Social Media Sign in, Payment SDKs, Maps

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Galixo ai / 9d Technology

Senior iOS Developer

Responsible for designing, coding, and deploying applications, involved in the complete development lifecycle from concept to release. Manage App Store Submissions, and ensure compliance.

App in Snap

Senior iOS Developer

As an iOS Developer at App in Snap, I am responsible for designing, developing, and implementing features and fixing production issues of our digital bank Zindigi iOS application using Swift.

May 2023 – Sep 2024 Islamabad, Pakistan

Sep 2024 - present

islamabad, Pakistan

Jul 2022 – May 2023 Islamabad

VEROKE *⊘*

iOS Developer

As an iOS Developer at VEROKE, I am responsible for designing, developing, and implementing features for our iOS applications using Swift. Conducting code reviews and implementing code improvements to enhance the quality of our iOS applications

In addition, I also develop native iOS modules for Flutter apps.

ARKHITECH Dec 2021 – Jul 2022

Islamabad, Pakistan

iOS Developer

As an iOS Developer at ARKHITECH, I was responsible for designing, developing, and implementing new features for iOS applications using Swift programming language.

I also provided some support for a flutter application.

IFISOLiOS Developer
Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Started as junior iOS developer, also learned flutter and worked as IOS / Flutter developer.

Took the responsibility of objective c , swift & Flutter projects.

PROJECTS

Zindigi (by JS Bank) ∂

https://apps.apple.com/app/id1592606621

Zindigi is a digital bank that allows Spend online and in-store, access trading, receive free international payments.

Its key features are Pay Bills, Investment in stocks and Mutual Funds, Money Transfer, Ticket Booking and Vouchers, Virtual debit cards.

Appical - the onboarding app ∂

https://apps.apple.com/pk/app/appical-the-onboarding-app/id1300083774 iOS app in Swift using MVVM and Snapkit for UI, which is designed to help multi-national companies manage and train their new hires effectively.

Manawanui 🔗

https://apps.apple.com/pk/app/manawanui/id1389753375
iOS application in Objective-C for the New Zealand Health Ministry responsible for assigning care takers for elderly citizens, managing time sheets, expenses of workers, and their payments and statements

⊘ مجموعة طبيب

id891683782/مجموعة -طبيب/id891683782

iOS application in Swift using MVVM architecture and SOLID for Saudi Arabia that allows users to browse through different offers from clinics in their city, book appointments, and make payments using multiple international and Saudi Arabia's local payment gateways

Urban Point ∂

https://apps.apple.com/pk/app/urban-point/id1074590743

iOS application in Swift that allows users to browse menus and place orders from their favorite restaurants. The app also included order tracking, delivery status updates, and a range of payment options for a seamless user experience.

Bolt VPN present

https://apps.apple.com/pk/app/bolt-vpn-super-fast-secure/id6738089266
Asecure VPN application supporting multiple protocols (OpenVPN, IKEv2, WireGuard) for enhanced user privacy and flexible connectivity. It also provides user temporary email and phone number.

HowMuch- Grocery Shopping *∂*

https://apps.apple.com/pk/app/howmuch-grocery-shopping/id991712504
An online shopping App in Flutter and Dart aimed at connecting buyers and sellers specifically in Pakistan. The main purpose is to facilitate both the sellers and the buyers in order to get them the best deals.

EDUCATION

BARANI ISTITUTE OF INFORMATION AND TECHNOLOGYBS Computer Science Rawalpindi, pakistan

GOVT GORDON COLLEGE

FSC PRE Engineering

SIR SYED PUBLIC SCHOOL

Matric science

2011 – 2013

Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Rawalpindi, Pakistan